<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>city representation on Ryan's Blog</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/tags/city-representation/</link><description>Recent content in city representation on Ryan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</managingEditor><webMaster>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhihaoruan.xyz/tags/city-representation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newcastle, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</guid><description>An overview of the city of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>London, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 20:52:13 +0000</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</guid><description>In this winter, I finally got a chance to visit and spend a nice Christmas holiday in UK.
Trafalgar Square
Tower Bridge
Christmas at Regent Street
London is famous for its theaters at West End. Along with New York City&amp;rsquo;s Broadway theatre, West End theatre is usually considered to represent the highest level of commercial theatre in the English-speaking world. Seeing a West End show is a common tourist activity in London.</description></item><item><title>Hong Kong, China</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 04:38:02 -0400</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/hong-kong/</guid><description>Hong Kong has been one of the fastest developing metropolis in China. When I was young, my impression of Hong Kong came with the Hong Kong TV shows. Hongkongers were so good at joking and acting that their movies and TV shows have had significant influences on me, especially with the fact that I can understand Cantonese :-). Not only me but also Chinese people in the 1980s and 1990s were greatly influenced by Hong Kong cultures.</description></item><item><title>Michigan, USA</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/michigan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 20:17:36 -0400</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/michigan/</guid><description>As a travelling enthusiast, there is no doubt that the state where I lived must somehow appear on my wishlist. During the two years in Ann Arbor, I also spent some time to explore Michigan.
What represents Michigan? It is very easy to think of the slogan of the State of Michigan — &amp;ldquo;Pure Michigan.&amp;rdquo; However, in what way does the State of Michigan look pure? Clearly it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the way in which Detroit and Lansing look.</description></item><item><title>Ireland</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/dublin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 20:36:02 -0400</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/dublin/</guid><description>Last summer, I went to Ireland for a trip. As a fan of the Irish boy band Westlife, I was really lucky to be able to get a ticket to their concert at Croke Park in Dublin. Meanwhile, I also had a chance to explore Dublin, a city with bars and Irish folk music.
Street Performers in Downtown Dublin To my great surprise, street performing seems to be a very popular activity in Dublin.</description></item><item><title>Ann Arbor, MI</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/ann-arbor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 22:08:00 -0400</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/ann-arbor/</guid><description>Ann Arbor is the place for me to pursue my second bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in the University of Michigan. It is a small but lovely town located in the south of the State of Michigan. While I was taking classes and working on the campus, I would also like to record those tiny little pieces of happiness in daily life with my lenses. These pictures help to keep my precious memories.</description></item><item><title>Zhuhai, China — Home, Sweet Home</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/zhuhai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 20:16:40 -0400</pubDate><author>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/zhuhai/</guid><description>Of all the places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, Zhuhai, by no doubt, is the most special one to me. I have been to almost everywhere in this city. As I grew up, countless changes have taken place in this city. People went and people came, and the city developed fast.
As a photographer, I have the feeling that it is my responsibility to record her changes every time I return. I really hope that my hometown can become better and better.</description></item></channel></rss>