<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ryan's Blog</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/</link><description>Yet another documentation of life.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</managingEditor><webMaster>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhihaoruan.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newcastle, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/newcastle/newcastle.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div> An overview of the city of Newcastle. The train station. City of Newcastle in the morning light. The two iconic bridges.</description></item><item><title>CAD2CAV: Computer Aided Design for Cooperative Autonomous Vehicles</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/cad2cav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 23:12:37 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/cad2cav/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/cad2cav/cad2cav-overview.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>CAD2CAV is a project focusing on multi-agent exploration in unknown environments. It attempts to build a complete system from perception to planning and control, exploring a designated unknown environments with multiple autonomous vehicles. It is built in xLab at the University of Pennsylvania, on multiple F1TENTH race cars.
Useful documents:
GitHub link Spring 2021 Final Report (not complete) Demo This is a sample scenario of a single F1TENTH race car exploring the 2nd floor of Levine Hall at the University of Pennsylvania, right outside xLab.</description></item><item><title>Volume Rendered ReSTIR in Vulkan</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-final-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-final-project/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/565-final-project/bunny.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This is a project of a Vulkan implementation of Fast Volume Rendering with Spatiotemporal Reservoir Resampling. It achieves the following:
Vulkan ray tracing pipeline with nvpro and Vulkan Ray Tracing KHR extension. Volume assets loading and rendering through OpenVDB. ReSTIR algorithm rendering on GLTF scene and volume assets. Authors Zhihao Ruan (ruanzh@seas.upenn.edu), Shubham Sharma (sshubh@seas.upenn.edu), Raymond Yang (rayyang@seas.upenn.edu) Tested on: Windows 10 Home 21H1 Build 19043.1288, Ryzen 7 3700X @ 3.</description></item><item><title>Vulkan Grass Rendering</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-vulkan-grass-rendering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:54:07 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-vulkan-grass-rendering/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/565-vulkan-grass-rendering/blade_upstraight.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Tested on: Windows 10 Home 21H1 Build 19043.1288, Ryzen 7 3700X @ 3.59GHz 48GB, RTX 2060 Super 8GB Highlights This project implements physically-based grass rendering &amp; culling with Vulkan compute shaders:
Physically-based real-time rendering of grass blades; 3 different culling tests: orientation culling, view-frustum culling, distance culling; Tessellating Bezier curves into grass blades with GLSL tessellation shader A detailed instruction of this project can be found here.
Vulkan Vulkan is considered as the next-generation graphics API developed by Khronos group, in replacement for the old OpenGL.]]></description></item><item><title>CUDA Path Tracer with À-Trous Denoiser</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-cuda-path-tracer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:43:29 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/565-cuda-path-tracer/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/565-cuda-path-tracer/cornell.2021-10-09_18-44-15z.5000samp.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Tested on: Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, Ryzen 3700X @ 2.22GHz 48GB, RTX 2060 Super @ 7976MB CUDA Path Tracer Highlights Finished path tracing core features:
diffuse shaders perfect specular reflection 1st-bounce ray intersection caching radix sort by material type path continuation/termination by Thrust stream compaction Finished Advanced Features:
Refraction with Fresnel effects using Schlick&rsquo;s approximation Stochastic sampled anti-aliasing Physically-based depth of field OBJ mesh loading with tinyobjloader Background: Ray Tracing Ray tracing is a technique commonly used in rendering.]]></description></item><item><title>London, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 20:52:13 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/london/_RZH3468postruanzh.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this winter, I finally got a chance to visit and spend a nice Christmas holiday in UK.
Trafalgar Square Tower Bridge Christmas at Regent Street London is famous for its theaters at West End. Along with New York City&rsquo;s Broadway theatre, West End theatre is usually considered to represent the highest level of commercial theatre in the English-speaking world. Seeing a West End show is a common tourist activity in London.]]></description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 6, Pure Pursuit (Waypoint Tracker)</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 19:52:14 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab6/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/f1tenth-lab6/f1tenth-lab6-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 4, Reactive Planning Methods for Obstacle Avoidance Overview In autonomous driving development, recording waypoints for future testing is very important.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 4, Reactive Planning Methods for Obstacle Avoidance</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 23:48:30 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab4/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/f1tenth-lab4/f1tenth-lab4.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower Overview Obstacle avoidance is one of the critical parts of autonomous driving. Crashing into obstacles could possibly bring serious damages to both the car and the object that it runs into.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 04:34:21 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab3/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/f1tenth-lab3/f1tenth-lab3-car.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking Lab Materials The lab materials can be accessed here. A PDF version is also attached here.
The lab was built on the F1Tenth Simulator, which can be accessed here.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 23:32:28 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/f1tenth-lab2/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/f1tenth-lab2/f1tenth-lab2.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS Overview This lab focuses on implementing an AEB (Automatic Emergency Braking) in ROS node for F1/10 racing cars. AEB is widely used in autonomous vehicles as a basic safety guarantee to avoid collisions with objects.
The lab materials can be accessed here.</description></item></channel></rss>