<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ryan's Blog</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on Ryan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhihaoruan.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newcastle, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/newcastle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/newcastle/</guid><description>An overview of the city of Newcastle.</description></item><item><title>CAD2CAV: Computer Aided Design for Cooperative Autonomous Vehicles</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/cad2cav/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 23:12:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/cad2cav/</guid><description>CAD2CAV is a project focusing on multi-agent exploration in unknown environments. It attempts to build a complete system from perception to planning and control, exploring a designated unknown environments with multiple autonomous vehicles. It is built in xLab at the University of Pennsylvania, on multiple F1TENTH race cars.
Useful documents:
GitHub link Spring 2021 Final Report (not complete) Demo This is a sample scenario of a single F1TENTH race car exploring the 2nd floor of Levine Hall at the University of Pennsylvania, right outside xLab.</description></item><item><title>Volume Rendered ReSTIR in Vulkan</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-final-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-final-project/</guid><description>This is a project of a Vulkan implementation of Fast Volume Rendering with Spatiotemporal Reservoir Resampling. It achieves the following:
Vulkan ray tracing pipeline with nvpro and Vulkan Ray Tracing KHR extension. Volume assets loading and rendering through OpenVDB. ReSTIR algorithm rendering on GLTF scene and volume assets. Authors Zhihao Ruan (ruanzh@seas.upenn.edu), Shubham Sharma (sshubh@seas.upenn.edu), Raymond Yang (rayyang@seas.upenn.edu) Tested on: Windows 10 Home 21H1 Build 19043.1288, Ryzen 7 3700X @ 3.</description></item><item><title>Vulkan Grass Rendering</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-vulkan-grass-rendering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:54:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-vulkan-grass-rendering/</guid><description>Tested on: Windows 10 Home 21H1 Build 19043.1288, Ryzen 7 3700X @ 3.59GHz 48GB, RTX 2060 Super 8GB Highlights This project implements physically-based grass rendering &amp;amp; culling with Vulkan compute shaders:
Physically-based real-time rendering of grass blades; 3 different culling tests: orientation culling, view-frustum culling, distance culling; Tessellating Bezier curves into grass blades with GLSL tessellation shader A detailed instruction of this project can be found here.
Vulkan Vulkan is considered as the next-generation graphics API developed by Khronos group, in replacement for the old OpenGL.</description></item><item><title>CUDA Path Tracer with À-Trous Denoiser</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-cuda-path-tracer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:43:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/565-cuda-path-tracer/</guid><description>Tested on: Ubuntu 20.04 LTS, Ryzen 3700X @ 2.22GHz 48GB, RTX 2060 Super @ 7976MB CUDA Path Tracer Highlights Finished path tracing core features:
diffuse shaders perfect specular reflection 1st-bounce ray intersection caching radix sort by material type path continuation/termination by Thrust stream compaction Finished Advanced Features:
Refraction with Fresnel effects using Schlick&amp;rsquo;s approximation Stochastic sampled anti-aliasing Physically-based depth of field OBJ mesh loading with tinyobjloader Background: Ray Tracing Ray tracing is a technique commonly used in rendering.</description></item><item><title>London, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/london/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 20:52:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/london/</guid><description>In this winter, I finally got a chance to visit and spend a nice Christmas holiday in UK.
Trafalgar Square
Tower Bridge
Christmas at Regent Street
London is famous for its theaters at West End. Along with New York City&amp;rsquo;s Broadway theatre, West End theatre is usually considered to represent the highest level of commercial theatre in the English-speaking world. Seeing a West End show is a common tourist activity in London.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 6, Pure Pursuit (Waypoint Tracker)</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 19:52:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab6/</guid><description>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 4, Reactive Planning Methods for Obstacle Avoidance Overview In autonomous driving development, recording waypoints for future testing is very important.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 4, Reactive Planning Methods for Obstacle Avoidance</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 23:48:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab4/</guid><description>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower Overview Obstacle avoidance is one of the critical parts of autonomous driving. Crashing into obstacles could possibly bring serious damages to both the car and the object that it runs into.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 3, PID-Controlled Wall Follower</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 04:34:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab3/</guid><description>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking Lab Materials The lab materials can be accessed here. A PDF version is also attached here.
Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: / The lab was built on the F1Tenth Simulator, which can be accessed here.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 2, Automatic Emergency Braking</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 23:32:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab2/</guid><description>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Previous post:
My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS Overview This lab focuses on implementing an AEB (Automatic Emergency Braking) in ROS node for F1/10 racing cars. AEB is widely used in autonomous vehicles as a basic safety guarantee to avoid collisions with objects.
The lab materials can be accessed here.</description></item><item><title>My F1TENTH Journey — Lab 1, Introduction to ROS</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:56:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/f1tenth-labs/f1tenth-lab1/</guid><description>This series of blogs marks the journey of my F1/10 Autonomous Racing Cars.
All my source codes can be accessed here.
Overview In Spring 2021 I finally got a chance to join the F1/10 Autonomous Racing Car Lab at Penn, supervised by Prof. Rahul Mangharam. To start my autonomous racing journey, I followed the official tutorials and studied the labs &amp;amp; projects there.
ROS (Robotics Operating System), is a robotics project development platform widely-used all across the world.</description></item><item><title>Minecraft Game Programming</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/560proj/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 18:30:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/560proj/</guid><description>In the fall of 2020, I finally had a chance to explore the field of computer graphics at University of Pennsylvania, and did a very interesting course project which builds a simplified Minecraft from scratch. This game is built on OpenGL 3.2 with Qt 5.15.0. Through building this game, I learned a lot about OpenGL rendering pipeline, game engine &amp;amp; texture mapping.
Demo Video Overview Minecraft is originally well-known for its block-like structure.</description></item><item><title>Real-Time On-Device Flow Statistics Detection and Prediction</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/450proj/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 17:40:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/450proj/</guid><description>This project was served as the Undergraduate Major Design Experience at UM-SJTU Joint Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University.
Background: The Impact of COVID-19 The outbreak of novel coronavirus COVID-19 in 2020 has brought huge attention to the administration of human society. &amp;ldquo;Social distancing&amp;rdquo; has been advocated as a very effective method to fight the virus. In order to facilitate the implementation of social distancing, we propose an idea of building a portable device that is capable of detect and predict flow statistics in real time, in order to provide insights and suggestions for traffic management.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Semiconductor Devices</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/lecturenotes/ve320-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 23:27:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/lecturenotes/ve320-notes/</guid><description>This post contains my lecture notes of taking the course VE320: Introduction to Semiconductor Devices at UM-SJTU Joint Institute.
Chapter 1: The Crystal Structure of Solids Unit cell vs. primitive cell primitive cell: smallest unit cell possible Three lattice types Simple cubic Body-centered cubic Face-centered cubic Volume density = $\dfrac{\text{number of atoms per unit cell}}{a^3}$ Unit: 1 Angstrom = 1e-10 m Miller Index: $(\frac{1}{x\text{-intersect}},\frac{1}{y\text{-intersect}},\frac{1}{z\text{-intersect}})\times\text{lcm}(x,y,z)$ (100) plane, (110) plane, (111) plane [100] direction, [110] direction, [111] direction Chapter 2: Introduction to Quantum Mechanics Plank&amp;rsquo;s constant: $h=6.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/introduction/</guid><description>Welcome to my personal website! I am a second-year robotics master&amp;rsquo;s student at the University of Pennsylvania. Prior to Penn, I received my B.S. degree in computer science engineering (CSE) at the University of Michigan, with a second B.S. degree in electrical and computer engineering (ECE) at Shanghai Jiao Tong University.
A picture of myself.
Relevant Classes With the advantage of being enrolled in a dual-degree program, I have taken a list of courses covering from electrical engineering to computer science, including but not limited to:</description></item><item><title>Witnessing the COVID-19 Pandemic</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 21:53:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/covid-19/</guid><description>As COVID-19 virus spread around the world causing serious pandemic and deaths, it also has seriously impacted countless people&amp;rsquo;s lives. As a resident in the United States, my everyday life has also been affected by this pandemic in multiple aspects. After making sure that social distancing can be properly kept when I was outdoors, I decided to take my camera and witness the changes of my daily life.
Ann Arbor, MI One of the most significant changes in my life is the wide use of face masks.</description></item><item><title>Capturing the "Blue Hour"</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/blue-hour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 20:23:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/blue-hour/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Blue Hour,&amp;rdquo; by definition, is the time period in a day when the world is covered in blue lights from the dusk or the dawn. It is usually formed in the period of twilight in the morning or in the evening when the sun is right below the horizon (more details check Wikipedia).
Blue hour is so famous due to its beauty. During this period, all the surroundings would be covered in the romantic blue, indicating the end of the day and the start of the night.</description></item><item><title>Hong Kong, China</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 04:38:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/hong-kong/</guid><description>Hong Kong has been one of the fastest developing metropolis in China. When I was young, my impression of Hong Kong came with the Hong Kong TV shows. Hongkongers were so good at joking and acting that their movies and TV shows have had significant influences on me, especially with the fact that I can understand Cantonese :-). Not only me but also Chinese people in the 1980s and 1990s were greatly influenced by Hong Kong cultures.</description></item><item><title>Michigan, USA</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/michigan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 20:17:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/michigan/</guid><description>As a travelling enthusiast, there is no doubt that the state where I lived must somehow appear on my wishlist. During the two years in Ann Arbor, I also spent some time to explore Michigan.
What represents Michigan? It is very easy to think of the slogan of the State of Michigan — &amp;ldquo;Pure Michigan.&amp;rdquo; However, in what way does the State of Michigan look pure? Clearly it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the way in which Detroit and Lansing look.</description></item><item><title>Ireland</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/dublin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 20:36:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/dublin/</guid><description>Last summer, I went to Ireland for a trip. As a fan of the Irish boy band Westlife, I was really lucky to be able to get a ticket to their concert at Croke Park in Dublin. Meanwhile, I also had a chance to explore Dublin, a city with bars and Irish folk music.
Street Performers in Downtown Dublin To my great surprise, street performing seems to be a very popular activity in Dublin.</description></item><item><title>SLAM — Simultaneous Localization And Mapping</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/467proj-slam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 23:47:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/467proj-slam/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simultaneous Localization And Mapping, also known as SLAM, is a set of very important techniques in robotics, and it&amp;rsquo;s still in active research. It aims at developing different algorithms for figuring out the position of the robot in the real world by the robot itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Interactive Game — Step On the White Tiles!</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/373proj/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 21:55:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/projects/373proj/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Probably one of the best interactive game projects I have seen in the class.&lt;/p>
— &lt;cite>Prof. Alanson Sample and Prof. Matt Smith, University of Michigan&lt;/cite>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;br>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;gt; &lt;em>This project is developed together with &lt;a href="https://regina8023.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Regina (Jingliang Ren)&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://voyager1998.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kun Huang&lt;/a> and Shiyu Liu.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/br>
&lt;strong>&amp;gt; &lt;em>This post is written in shared effort with &lt;a href="https://regina8023.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Regina (Jingliang Ren)&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/br>
&lt;strong>&amp;gt; &lt;em>Special thanks to them for all their contributions!&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ann Arbor, MI</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/ann-arbor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 22:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/ann-arbor/</guid><description>Ann Arbor is the place for me to pursue my second bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in the University of Michigan. It is a small but lovely town located in the south of the State of Michigan. While I was taking classes and working on the campus, I would also like to record those tiny little pieces of happiness in daily life with my lenses. These pictures help to keep my precious memories.</description></item><item><title>Zhuhai, China — Home, Sweet Home</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/zhuhai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 20:16:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/posts/gallery/zhuhai/</guid><description>Of all the places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to, Zhuhai, by no doubt, is the most special one to me. I have been to almost everywhere in this city. As I grew up, countless changes have taken place in this city. People went and people came, and the city developed fast.
As a photographer, I have the feeling that it is my responsibility to record her changes every time I return. I really hope that my hometown can become better and better.</description></item></channel></rss>