<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>photography - Tag - Ryan's Blog</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/tags/photography/</link><description>photography - Tag - Ryan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</managingEditor><webMaster>shineyruan@gmail.com (Zhihao Ruan)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:02:13 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhihaoruan.xyz/tags/photography/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>California Poppy &amp;mdash; A Splendid Spring!</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/california-poppy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 02:02:13 -0700</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/california-poppy/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/rzhpost-2796.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The winter of 2022&ndash;2023 has been an extremely wet one for California. The cold air from the North Pole rages down into the southern part of U.S. west coast, turning into heavy rain and snow. However, as a positive result, California is very likely to greet a splendid &ldquo;super bloom&rdquo; after several years of drought.
Of all the flowers, California Poppy could be one of the most iconic flower species that worth a visit.]]></description></item><item><title>Newcastle, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:42:55 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/newcastle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/newcastle/newcastle.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div> An overview of the city of Newcastle. The train station. City of Newcastle in the morning light. The two iconic bridges.</description></item><item><title>London, UK</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 20:52:13 +0000</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/london/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/london/_RZH3468postruanzh.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this winter, I finally got a chance to visit and spend a nice Christmas holiday in UK.
Trafalgar Square Tower Bridge Christmas at Regent Street London is famous for its theaters at West End. Along with New York City&rsquo;s Broadway theatre, West End theatre is usually considered to represent the highest level of commercial theatre in the English-speaking world. Seeing a West End show is a common tourist activity in London.]]></description></item><item><title>Witnessing the COVID-19 Pandemic</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 21:53:56 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/covid-19/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/covid-19/RZH8556post.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>As COVID-19 virus spread around the world causing serious pandemic and deaths, it also has seriously impacted countless people&rsquo;s lives. As a resident in the United States, my everyday life has also been affected by this pandemic in multiple aspects. After making sure that social distancing can be properly kept when I was outdoors, I decided to take my camera and witness the changes of my daily life.
Ann Arbor, MI ]]></description></item><item><title>Capturing the "Blue Hour"</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/blue-hour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 20:23:20 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/blue-hour/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/blue-hour/RZH8702post.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>&ldquo;Blue Hour,&rdquo; by definition, is the time period in a day when the world is covered in blue lights from the dusk or the dawn. It is usually formed in the period of twilight in the morning or in the evening when the sun is right below the horizon (more details check Wikipedia).
Blue hour is so famous due to its beauty. During this period, all the surroundings would be covered in the romantic blue, indicating the end of the day and the start of the night.]]></description></item><item><title>Hong Kong, China</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 04:38:02 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/hong-kong/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/hong-kong/DSC00851.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Hong Kong has been one of the fastest developing metropolis in China. When I was young, my impression of Hong Kong came with the Hong Kong TV shows. Hongkongers were so good at joking and acting that their movies and TV shows have had significant influences on me, especially with the fact that I can understand Cantonese :-). Not only me but also Chinese people in the 1980s and 1990s were greatly influenced by Hong Kong cultures.</description></item><item><title>Michigan, USA</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/michigan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 20:17:36 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/michigan/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/michigan/CZQ190818DSC02076.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>As a travelling enthusiast, there is no doubt that the state where I lived must somehow appear on my wishlist. During the two years in Ann Arbor, I also spent some time to explore Michigan.
What represents Michigan? It is very easy to think of the slogan of the State of Michigan — &ldquo;Pure Michigan.&rdquo; However, in what way does the State of Michigan look pure? Clearly it shouldn&rsquo;t be the way in which Detroit and Lansing look.]]></description></item><item><title>Ireland</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/dublin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 20:36:02 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/dublin/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/posts/ireland/RZH403524.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Last summer, I went to Ireland for a trip. As a fan of the Irish boy band Westlife, I was really lucky to be able to get a ticket to their concert at Croke Park in Dublin. Meanwhile, I also had a chance to explore Dublin, a city with bars and Irish folk music.
Street Performers in Downtown Dublin To my great surprise, street performing seems to be a very popular activity in Dublin.</description></item><item><title>Ann Arbor, MI</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/ann-arbor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 22:08:00 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/ann-arbor/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/ann-arbor/RZH4586A190807.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Ann Arbor is the place for me to pursue my second bachelor&rsquo;s degree in the University of Michigan. It is a small but lovely town located in the south of the State of Michigan. While I was taking classes and working on the campus, I would also like to record those tiny little pieces of happiness in daily life with my lenses. These pictures help to keep my precious memories.]]></description></item><item><title>Zhuhai, China — Home, Sweet Home</title><link>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/zhuhai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 20:16:40 -0400</pubDate><author>Zhihao Ruan</author><guid>https://zhihaoruan.xyz/zhuhai/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/posts/zhuhai/DSC00222.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Of all the places I&rsquo;ve been to, Zhuhai, by no doubt, is the most special one to me. I have been to almost everywhere in this city. As I grew up, countless changes have taken place in this city. People went and people came, and the city developed fast.
As a photographer, I have the feeling that it is my responsibility to record her changes every time I return. I really hope that my hometown can become better and better.]]></description></item></channel></rss>